<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Written on Griffin Steffy</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/written/</link><description>Recent content in Written on Griffin Steffy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/written/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5 Things I'm Thankful For...That Start With The Letter F</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/5-things-im-thankful-for...that-start-with-the-letter-f/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/5-things-im-thankful-for...that-start-with-the-letter-f/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is typical this time of year for everyone to share things that they are thankful for having in their lives. I typically do not like to follow trends, but when I was listing out my top handful I noticed that a majority of them started with the same letter. Since I found that comical, I decided to share it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Family
I think this could go without an explanation, but regardless I&amp;rsquo;ll give a brief one. Since moving back home closer to family I really have noticed a big difference in my life. I am more willing to ask for help, and actually enjoy spending time with my family much more than years past. This is going to be the first holiday season where I am no longer traveling to see people for the holidays, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get to sleep in my own bed the same night we get together. I believe being able to chose to spend time with family, instead of being forced to has made a huge difference.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Friends
Ever since college the time I get to spend with my friends has dwindled dramatically. This is mostly because we are scattered throughout the nation (and world currently), but it has forced me to reflect on how much I need to enjoy the time I do get with my friends. I&amp;rsquo;m thankful for the time we have gotten to spend together, even though it is few and far between as of recent.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fitness
After moving into our house, I had a realization why it is so important to maintain my fitness. I am not sure how people move furniture around the way we did without some sort of physical training. It definitely was not easy, but we leaned hard on my and my families physical fitness to move tons of furniture up and down stairs. Looking forward to what I have in store for my life, I am glad that I maintain a level of fitness that will allow me to continue to do hard things.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Football
Purely for entertainment, the sport of Football has brought me tons of joy in the past two years. My family has been through countless changes, and when I get the chance to sit down on the couch and watch a game, or turn it on in the background, I truly enjoy every minute I get to watch of America&amp;rsquo;s game.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Freedom
Living in a country where we have the freedom that we have is a blessing. I know I take it for granted every day, and only if I were in the other situation would I know just how good we have it over here in the United States.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Coffee Database</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/coffee-database/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 20:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/coffee-database/</guid><description>&lt;p>Even though I switched to obsidian for my second brain, I still value Notion as a tool for organizing information. The true power of notion is in it&amp;rsquo;s database capabilities which is why it is a top choice for a lot of people&amp;rsquo;s second brain.
I still take advantage of Notion&amp;rsquo;s strength by creating a coffee database for all of the different beans and roasters that I have tried for about the last 2 years. This is something I used to do in an Apple Note, but it is much easier to maintain inside of a database.
I started out keeping track of different beans that I tried because someday I was going to forget what beans I had tried, and which ones I hav not. This then expanded into a rough ranking system so if I ever did want to try beans again, then I knew which ones were my favorites, and as time has continued I have kept adding metadata to each entry to provide as much useful information I&amp;rsquo;ll need regarding coffee beans.
Here is the link to my &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/griffinsteffy/032fb06e7d594cc5a7c777cb1e88c8e8?v=59c9128356674ff08dd849e3a7cc4398&amp;amp;pvs=4">coffee bean database&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Watering Our Plant</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/watering-our-plant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 22:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/watering-our-plant/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am not a plant expert, and I really have only sort of cared about taking care of them for almost a year, but as I was watered our birds of paradise tonight I figured that sharing my process is something that is worth sharing.
We got a birds of paradise plant last year for my wife&amp;rsquo;s birthday, and I saw &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; because it is technically her plant but I have taken over watering responsibilities since she has gotten too big for her to pick up on her own. Regardless the plant&amp;rsquo;s name is Gwen and we&amp;rsquo;re happy to have her in our home.
After doing a few google searches we learned that bottom feeding was the easiest and most effective way to promote health plant growth (along with sufficient sunlight). When the plant was small in its starter planter it was easy to lift it up into our kitchen sink and let her sit overnight. Since she has outgrown the sink we moved to the bathtub.
Our process is pretty simple&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Use Todoist</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/how-i-use-todoist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 21:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/how-i-use-todoist/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my original outline of my Second Brain I briefly described how I store my tasks. Since then, I have had time to get through a few iterations of my workflow using this specific application.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily my favorite things that drew me to the app initially are all still true, and most likely even more reinforced. It is quick to add task, organize them, and complete them as they come up. The cross-platform availability is what really gets me excited about talking about &lt;a href="https://todoist.com/">Todoist&lt;/a>. I have mentioned that my work computer is a Windows machine, and I would like to use arguably the most crucial part of my second brain the 40+ hours a week I am using my work computer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Halfway There</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/halfway-there/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/halfway-there/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started this website as an experiment, but also as a low pressure creative outlet for myself. This marks the 26th piece that goes live on this site, and as cliche as it sounds, it has gone much quicker than I would have imagined. I am proud of what I have published so far, and even though there have been some rough patches, I am still glad that it is something I started, and am looking forward to finishing out the 2nd half.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cramping Expectations</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/cramping-expectations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/cramping-expectations/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have never been a heavy user of social media, but I noticed about a month ago that I was starting to spend more time than usual scrolling. Having an iPhone, I actually have had a time limit setup for over a year, but have ignored it almost every time.
After I noticed that my mindless scrolling was starting to take away from doing things that I enjoy, and bring me happiness I decided to just delete all social media from my phone. It helps that I talk to all of my friends in dedicated messaging apps, so I did not lose any meaningful connections of mine by making this change.
Not only was it taking up time I could use better elsewhere, social media has this effect to limit expectations in life. It is great to look up to others, but through the phone screen I end up setting my expectations to what everyone else has accomplished. My work becomes limited by what others have done, and not by what my own mind can create.
I have struggled the last few months to get content up on this website. Even with potentially the lowest barrier to entry for uploading content, I still feel like I am fishing for ideas on a weekly basis. Since making this change it has gotten slightly better, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that years of limiting my expectations, while also trying to be somewhat creative are two forces fighting against each other.
I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself adding back any of the social media apps anytime soon. They were making too big of an impact on what I want to accomplish, hoping that my creativity begins to flourish without having an established ceiling on top of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christmas Light Learnings</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/christmas-light-learnings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/christmas-light-learnings/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a first time homeowner, I have never had the opportunity to decorate the outside of my own home for Christmas until now. I always loved helping my dad put up lights, but when you are a kid, you do not realize how much actually goes into a task that seems so simple. Not that the task is very difficult, but I did want to record a few things I learned, and lessons that I&amp;rsquo;ll take into next year when I go for round two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Work Fit</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/my-work-fit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/my-work-fit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Working as an embedded developer I do acknowledge that I have a lot of luxuries. I am blessed to have a great job, work for a great company who cares about its employees, and have the freedom to express myself through what I wear to work.
I have not been in the working world as long as others, but in my short time, I have discovered a few things that I enjoy wearing to maintain productivity and comfortability throughout the work day. Here are the three things I wear to the office almost every day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Questions</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/life-questions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/life-questions/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>What would you do if you had financial freedom?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What does it look like to discover and pursue God&amp;rsquo;s Calling?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are some tools I can immediately use to better discover my calling?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can I integrate my faith into my everyday work?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Where does something cross from being too hard to learn into not worth your time to pursue?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Successful Cross-Section</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/successful-cross-section/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/successful-cross-section/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was listening to the latest episode of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yiukwi_3n_A">Matti Haapoja Podcast&lt;/a> and the discussion came up around the relationship between an obsession and skill.
In their conversation they were discussing a successful career and ways that someone can achieve it. Essentially it is where an obsession and skill align, but finding that middle ground tends to be the tough part.
For myself, I know specific things that I am skilled at, and others that I am currently obsessing over. I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the hunt for finding an area where the two overlap but have not found the silver bullet yet.
Matti was already a great film maker, and he became obsessed with making a business to teach people. Out of that combination has grown a very successful YouTube channel, and many other related businesses.
I hope someday I find the cross-section of obsession and skill, and when I do, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to reflect back to this moment when I feel like I will never get there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smart Home Starter Pack</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/smart-home-starter-pack/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/smart-home-starter-pack/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been slowly building out a smart home for almost 3 years now, but only in the last 9 months have I actually made some significant progress. I think back to how I started building out my system, and thinking to myself how I wish I had better spent my dollars. Below is my suggested start pack for those who are starting anew smart home.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Smart thermostat
I would guess that a majority of people begin their smart home with one of two things, the main one being a smart thermostat. Not only is it super fun to control your home from miles away, but adding a smart thermostat can save you dollars on your utility bill. Also, in some areas your utility company will give you rebates or discounts that practically make the device free! A smart thermostat is a no brainer for any home owner in my opinion, regardless if you have ambitions to build the smart home any further.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Smart Lock
A smart lock probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be most people choice, but the reason I have it placed second is similar to the thermostat, the value a smart lock provides is much higher than most entry level items. Although they tend to be a bit pricy they give you more sense of security knowing that you can check if you locked the door when you are away from home, lock it if you didn&amp;rsquo;t, and then move on with your day. If you aspirations are to add one eventually, I would save up for a bit longer and skip all of the less expensive options initially and add much more value by adding a smart lock.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Smart Light Switch
This would probably not make most people list, but in lieu of not mentioning a smart light bulb, I think a smart light switch is much more valuable to a home than a single bulb. Typically updating a home to be smart comes with training of other house member. Smart lights are the epitome of this by constantly trying to convince whoever it is not to turn off the lamp you have set on a timer. Although this is harmless, it can still be frustrating. Thus is why I believe a smart light switch is a better add to a starting smart home. There is no training, if they accidentally press the light switch, there is no loss of connection, just either a routine acceleration or deviation. Either of these are fine as they will be corrected at the next schedule turning point. Smart light switches are a great add to any home, allowing for soft exposure to the entire household to living in a smart home.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Building a smart home is not easy, and definitely not cheap. If I were to start over again I would first add the items that provide the most value per dollar, not necessarily the lowest dollar amount. Unfortunately, many go the later route and lose interest because they no longer see the benefit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Coffee Routine</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/my-coffee-routine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/my-coffee-routine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coffee comes as a forced taste to me, I actually couldn&amp;rsquo;t even take a sip of it until a little over three years ago. What I did enjoy was the scent and vibe that coffee carries with it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to turn into a latte lover though, so I set a requirement for myself that in order to start making coffee on a regular basis I was going to enjoy drinking it black. I did not realize that this requirement I set for myself would then send me down a rabbit hole on how to make great tasting black cups of coffee in the morning versus the typical drip or pod machines. I started the journey using a French Press, moved quickly to an AeroPress for a whole year, and then finally moved to a chemex and have been there ever since. I still enjoy using the other tools, you can make great coffee out of almost anything actually, but I feel like I have settled down to a morning routine that I don&amp;rsquo;t see making drastic changes to for quite some time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making Small Changes</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/making-small-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/making-small-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Buying a house can be simplified to a single transaction of an asset; I never viewed it that way, but my expectations for how I would be emotionally effected were not even close. My prediction was that I would be elated to move into my families first home together, and even though there would be challenges I would be so happy to be there that I would not let those challenges phase me. I still had those elated feelings, sometimes I still feel like my life isn&amp;rsquo;t real, but I seemed to be more sunk into reality that I know have a lot more responsibility than I have ever had before.
I did not prepare myself for the emotional toll that these new responsibilities would weigh on my mind. Since we have moved in I feel like my creativity has been at an all time low since starting this project. I find my self coming up wit titles, but nothing more ever comes from those ideas zipping past me. On top of that, we haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to make many changes to the place, because we are just trying to figure it out as we go, so we have yet to put our stamp on the place.
I can go on and on about how I feel like I am now on the way up mentally from this home purchasing experience, but what started it all was beginning to make our home feel like it is ours. We have been holding back on making and major cosmetic changes for the first month or two to make sure our finances are in order. I believe that regardless of what stress I have now, adding some financial stress on top of it cannot make it better. Knowing that, we still decided that it was time to paint (we might have been pushed a little after we discovered that there was a 40% off sale). Paint seemed like one of the least expensive changes we could make, and we want to do it anyway so no long term loss if it didn&amp;rsquo;t make a difference.
After painting our bedroom, I can assure you that I feel much better about sleeping in there at night, purely by how I feel when I walk in the room. I can only describe it as putting our mark on the home, and no longer are we living in someone else&amp;rsquo;s space. All it took was a few gallons of paint, and for us to borrow some paint supplies from our family to turn things around. We didn&amp;rsquo;t eliminate any problems, all we did was give the walls a facelift and it has kicked us off in the right direction.
All of a sudden I can feel my creative flow coming back, and am more motivated to keep pressing towards my goals that I have laid out before. This experience has me thinking, I wonder what other small changes I can make in other areas of my life that could have a larger impact than what they would cost me. Often it is the smallest changes that make the biggest difference.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The State of My Second Brain</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/the-state-of-my-second-brain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/the-state-of-my-second-brain/</guid><description>&lt;p>I first discovered the concept of a second brain in the late spring, as I was in the middle of organizing my life. I was dealing with files, tasks, events, and projects that I was thinking about starting. To be honest I wasn’t that disorganized beforehand, but what I was looking for was a structure to follow when new projects or ideas come up. I found that when a new idea would pop in my head, I scrambled to find the best place to at least record that idea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Switched to Obsidian</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/i-switched-to-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/i-switched-to-obsidian/</guid><description>&lt;p>Almost 3 months I gave a comprehensive explanation of [[4 Notes/Blog Posts/The State of My Second Brain]], or personal knowledge management system (PKM). At the time I was using &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so">Notion&lt;/a> as the heart of everything, but I quickly ran into some of its limitations shortly after that content went live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I found the most frustrating about Notion, was the need for a internet connection to access your entire workspace. This is not new information, it is one of the biggest complaints about the tool, but in my mind I did not think that I would ever run into this, because we live in 2022. I then realized how often I was inside of large auditoriums where I typically like to take notes (ie. Church, conferences, etc.) and there I didn&amp;rsquo;t have connection to view the entire workspace I had built for over a month. Notion does cache recent and frequent pages that you open, but the whole idea of a PKM is that you can access your whole library, not just what you could access in your first brain (recent and frequent).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Right Opportunity</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/the-right-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/the-right-opportunity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our Family just recently got an accepted offer on a house, and we are every excited to move into that next phase of life. Owning some property is something that we have had in the back of our minds since we have been married. Even though we have enjoyed the renting phase as we go through various life transitions, there have been countless times where we wish we just owned the place where we lived. This is not a knock on renting, certain lifestyles, and life situations definitely cater more to the renter. We were traveling a lot for work, growing our family, moving states, and changing jobs; no way could we have been taking care of a homestead in the midst of all of those life changes. Renting has provided us flexibility, and the ability to wait for the right opportunity to move into home ownership.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quiet Strength by Tony Dungy</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/quiet-strength-by-tony-dungy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/quiet-strength-by-tony-dungy/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="what-are-recaps">What are Recaps?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Recaps are not reviews, but more of a way to translate my notes I take while reading/watching/listening to content into planned out thoughts. Don’t expect me to give you a star rating, or a sparknotes style review that allows you to not read the book. These are just thoughts I had, interesting points, and overall themes that I noticed throughout content consumption.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="family-is-everything">Family is Everything&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If there is one thing I picked up from reading Tony Dungy’s first book, it is that family is everything. Of course the whole book has football related references, stories of his time in the NFL, and many other great snippets of life advice, but overall what I have in big letters in my notebook is “Family is Everything.” There is no other group of people that know you better than your family. Family does not have to be blood related, and a better word for it might be something cheesy like “circle of trust”. Regardless, I consider family to be those who love you the most, and who you love the most. Everyone has a different shape that surrounds who they’d call “family,” but cherishing time with them is something that I need to constantly remind myself. It can be easy to isolate myself, because I know what I like the best, but if God wanted us to live alone, I don’t think Eve would have ever joined Adam in the garden of Eden.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I've Read the Bible 838 Times</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</guid><description>&lt;p>On January 1st, 2020 I set a goal in my mind to read the entire Bible that year. My goal was to read a piece of it every day, and by the end of the year, I will have read the entire book cover to cover (essentially).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a few days I rediscovered the &lt;a href="https://oneyearbibleonline.com">The One Year Bible&lt;/a>, which provided more of a structure to my reading plan. This allowed me to offload the mental process of deciding how much I should read that day, and just focus on reading. The obvious benefit here was saving time, but it also allowed me to focus more on the content and not constantly looking for my next stopping point as I read. 838 Days in and I am by no means an expert on the Bible, I have just read through it a few times, but since starting this habit I have learned 3 key lessons…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Semi-Rural Home Internet</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/semi-rural-home-internet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/semi-rural-home-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>My family recently ended our time living in an apartment and found a home in a semi-rural area. I say semi-rural because we are surrounded by cornfields and country homes, but are 3 minutes from a business park, and 3 minutes form three different interstate exits. Unfortunately, even with the business development happening near out home, the residential infrastructure has not kept up. I work in the tech space, and to be short I am a power user of our home internet service. Whether it is video calls for work, streaming high quality videos, or other personal projects (this site included); I am constantly uploading and downloading from a server somewhere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/purpose/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/purpose/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-idea-behind-it">The Idea Behind It&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If there is one thing you should know about me is that I am not a confident writer. As I wrote papers during school, I tended to procrastinate (maybe like yourself). However, I’m not sure I always waited till the last minute due to a lack of an idea. Sometimes it was no motivation to write, but looking back I do not think that was always the case.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FFP (Fastest Feasible Product)</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ffp-fastest-feasible-product/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ffp-fastest-feasible-product/</guid><description>&lt;p>The hurdle of perfection is one of the hardest to get over when it comes to starting a project. I wonder how many projects I failed to start, because the ideal ending seemed like too daunting of a task. It sounds easy to take one step at a time, but when the main focus is perfection the road will never end, and taking a small step seems like a drop in the ocean.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>