<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Written on Griffin Steffy</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/written/</link><description>Recent content in Written on Griffin Steffy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/written/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I've Read the Bible 838 Times</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</guid><description>&lt;p>On January 1st, 2020 I set a goal in my mind to read the entire Bible that year. My goal was to read a piece of it every day, and by the end of the year, I will have read the entire book cover to cover (essentially).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a few days I rediscovered the &lt;a href="https://oneyearbibleonline.com">The One Year Bible&lt;/a>, which provided more of a structure to my reading plan. This allowed me to offload the mental process of deciding how much I should read that day, and just focus on reading. The obvious benefit here was saving time, but it also allowed me to focus more on the content and not constantly looking for my next stopping point as I read. 838 Days in and I am by no means an expert on the Bible, I have just read through it a few times, but since starting this habit I have learned 3 key lessons…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/purpose/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/purpose/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-idea-behind-it">The Idea Behind It&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If there is one thing you should know about me is that I am not a confident writer. As I wrote papers during school, I tended to procrastinate (maybe like yourself). However, I’m not sure I always waited till the last minute due to a lack of an idea. Sometimes it was no motivation to write, but looking back I do not think that was always the case.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FFP (Fastest Feasible Product)</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ffp-fastest-feasible-product/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ffp-fastest-feasible-product/</guid><description>&lt;p>The hurdle of perfection is one of the hardest to get over when it comes to starting a project. I wonder how many projects I failed to start, because the ideal ending seemed like too daunting of a task. It sounds easy to take one step at a time, but when the main focus is perfection the road will never end, and taking a small step seems like a drop in the ocean.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>