<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Griffin Steffy</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on Griffin Steffy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 13:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I've Read the Bible 838 Times</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</guid><description>&lt;p>On January 1st, 2020 I set a goal in my mind to read the entire Bible that year. My goal was to read a piece of it every day, and by the end of the year, I will have read the entire book cover to cover (essentially).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a few days I rediscovered the &lt;a href="https://oneyearbibleonline.com">The One Year Bible&lt;/a>, which provided more of a structure to my reading plan. This allowed me to offload the mental process of deciding how much I should read that day, and just focus on reading. The obvious benefit here was saving time, but it also allowed me to focus more on the content and not constantly looking for my next stopping point as I read. 838 Days in and I am by no means an expert on the Bible, I have just read through it a few times, but since starting this habit I have learned 3 key lessons…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Ton of Bricks</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/a-ton-of-bricks-fp-pt-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/a-ton-of-bricks-fp-pt-1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-ton-of-bricks">A Ton of Bricks&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I was very naive as a college graduate when it came to my finances. I generally knew how to save money, be frugal with my spending, but my actual my applicable knowledge of finances was novice at best. Having just graduated from a prestigious engineer school, I had accepted my first real job, was moving to another state, and was prepping to get married that summer, life was great. It wasn’t that I didn’t know what was coming my way, I just did not understand the gap of knowledge that I had to make up. The good news was that I had time on my side to figure things out before they really became a problem.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>