<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on Hugo Bootstrap Theme</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on Hugo Bootstrap Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Open-source &lt;a class=&#34;text-muted text-decoration-none&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/filipecarneiro/hugo-bootstrap-theme/blob/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; Licensed.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:20:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quiet Strength by Tony Dungy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/quiet-strength-by-tony-dungy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/quiet-strength-by-tony-dungy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-recaps&#34;&gt;What are Recaps?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recaps are not reviews, but more of a way to translate my notes I take while reading/watching/listening to content into planned out thoughts. Don’t expect me to give you a star rating, or a sparknotes style review that allows you to not read the book. These are just thoughts I had, interesting points, and overall themes that I noticed throughout content consumption.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;family-is-everything&#34;&gt;Family is Everything&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing I picked up from reading Tony Dungy’s first book, it is that family is everything. Of course the whole book has football related references, stories of his time in the NFL, and many other great snippets of life advice, but overall what I have in big letters in my notebook is “Family is Everything.” There is no other group of people that know you better than your family. Family does not have to be blood related, and a better word for it might be something cheesy like “circle of trust”. Regardless, I consider family to be those who love you the most, and who you love the most. Everyone has a different shape that surrounds who they’d call “family,” but cherishing time with them is something that I need to constantly remind myself. It can be easy to isolate myself, because I know what I like the best, but if God wanted us to live alone, I don’t think Eve would have ever joined Adam in the garden of Eden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve Read the Bible 838 Times</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ive-read-the-bible-838-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 1st, 2020 I set a goal in my mind to read the entire Bible that year. My goal was to read a piece of it every day, and by the end of the year, I will have read the entire book cover to cover (essentially).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a few days I rediscovered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://oneyearbibleonline.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The One Year Bible&lt;/a&gt;, which provided more of a structure to my reading plan. This allowed me to offload the mental process of deciding how much I should read that day, and just focus on reading. The obvious benefit here was saving time, but it also allowed me to focus more on the content and not constantly looking for my next stopping point as I read. 838 Days in and I am by no means an expert on the Bible, I have just read through it a few times, but since starting this habit I have learned 3 key lessons…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
