<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Review on Griffin Steffy</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/review/</link><description>Recent content in Review on Griffin Steffy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 11:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Halfway There</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/halfway-there/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/halfway-there/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started this website as an experiment, but also as a low pressure creative outlet for myself. This marks the 26th piece that goes live on this site, and as cliche as it sounds, it has gone much quicker than I would have imagined. I am proud of what I have published so far, and even though there have been some rough patches, I am still glad that it is something I started, and am looking forward to finishing out the 2nd half.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Semi-Rural Home Internet</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/semi-rural-home-internet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/semi-rural-home-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>My family recently ended our time living in an apartment and found a home in a semi-rural area. I say semi-rural because we are surrounded by cornfields and country homes, but are 3 minutes from a business park, and 3 minutes form three different interstate exits. Unfortunately, even with the business development happening near out home, the residential infrastructure has not kept up. I work in the tech space, and to be short I am a power user of our home internet service. Whether it is video calls for work, streaming high quality videos, or other personal projects (this site included); I am constantly uploading and downloading from a server somewhere.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>