<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Hugo Bootstrap Theme</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Hugo Bootstrap Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Open-source &lt;a class=&#34;text-muted text-decoration-none&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/filipecarneiro/hugo-bootstrap-theme/blob/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; Licensed.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:20:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life Questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/life-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/life-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What would you do if you had financial freedom?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What does it look like to discover and pursue God&amp;rsquo;s Calling?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What are some tools I can immediately use to better discover my calling?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How can I integrate my faith into my everyday work?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Where does something cross from being too hard to learn into not worth your time to pursue?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Successful Cross-Section</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/successful-cross-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/successful-cross-section/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was listening to the latest episode of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yiukwi_3n_A&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Matti Haapoja Podcast&lt;/a&gt; and the discussion came up around the relationship between an obsession and skill.&#xA;In their conversation they were discussing a successful career and ways that someone can achieve it. Essentially it is where an obsession and skill align, but finding that middle ground tends to be the tough part.&#xA;For myself, I know specific things that I am skilled at, and others that I am currently obsessing over. I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the hunt for finding an area where the two overlap but have not found the silver bullet yet.&#xA;Matti was already a great film maker, and he became obsessed with making a business to teach people. Out of that combination has grown a very successful YouTube channel, and many other related businesses.&#xA;I hope someday I find the cross-section of obsession and skill, and when I do, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to reflect back to this moment when I feel like I will never get there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FFP (Fastest Feasible Product)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ffp-fastest-feasible-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ffp-fastest-feasible-product/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hurdle of perfection is one of the hardest to get over when it comes to starting a project. I wonder how many projects I failed to start, because the ideal ending seemed like too daunting of a task. It sounds easy to take one step at a time, but when the main focus is perfection the road will never end, and taking a small step seems like a drop in the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-idea-behind-it&#34;&gt;The Idea Behind It&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing you should know about me is that I am not a confident writer. As I wrote papers during school, I tended to procrastinate (maybe like yourself). However, I’m not sure I always waited till the last minute due to a lack of an idea. Sometimes it was no motivation to write, but looking back I do not think that was always the case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
