<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Griffin Steffy</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Griffin Steffy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cramping Expectations</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/cramping-expectations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/cramping-expectations/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have never been a heavy user of social media, but I noticed about a month ago that I was starting to spend more time than usual scrolling. Having an iPhone, I actually have had a time limit setup for over a year, but have ignored it almost every time.
After I noticed that my mindless scrolling was starting to take away from doing things that I enjoy, and bring me happiness I decided to just delete all social media from my phone. It helps that I talk to all of my friends in dedicated messaging apps, so I did not lose any meaningful connections of mine by making this change.
Not only was it taking up time I could use better elsewhere, social media has this effect to limit expectations in life. It is great to look up to others, but through the phone screen I end up setting my expectations to what everyone else has accomplished. My work becomes limited by what others have done, and not by what my own mind can create.
I have struggled the last few months to get content up on this website. Even with potentially the lowest barrier to entry for uploading content, I still feel like I am fishing for ideas on a weekly basis. Since making this change it has gotten slightly better, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that years of limiting my expectations, while also trying to be somewhat creative are two forces fighting against each other.
I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself adding back any of the social media apps anytime soon. They were making too big of an impact on what I want to accomplish, hoping that my creativity begins to flourish without having an established ceiling on top of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The State of My Second Brain</title><link>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/the-state-of-my-second-brain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.griffinsteffy.com/posts/the-state-of-my-second-brain/</guid><description>&lt;p>I first discovered the concept of a second brain in the late spring, as I was in the middle of organizing my life. I was dealing with files, tasks, events, and projects that I was thinking about starting. To be honest I wasn’t that disorganized beforehand, but what I was looking for was a structure to follow when new projects or ideas come up. I found that when a new idea would pop in my head, I scrambled to find the best place to at least record that idea.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>